TAUFIQUL ALAM

 $+880-1896-117322 \diamond$ Dhaka, Bangladesh

taufiqul.alam1207@gmail.com \diamond LinkedIn \diamond GitHub

INTRODUCTION

A firm believer in the life-long pursuit of learning. Good at adapting and changing to become the best at whatever the task at hand is.

An expert in various powerful programming languages, with an in-depth knowledge of mathematics, Game Engines, 3D Graphics, GPU, and Desktop Hardware Programming.

With a keen interest in Video Games, Multimedia, and Interactive media development and research.

EDUCATION

Bachelor of Computer Science and Engineering, Islamic University of Technology, Dhaka CGPA: $3.68 \ / \ 4.00$

2023

SKILLS

Programming Languages	C, C++, C#, GLSL, HLSL, CG, Java, Python, Javascript, Rust, Dart
Frameworks/Libraries/APIs	CUDA, CUDNN, Qt(5/6), Dear ImGUI, OpenGL, SDL, SFML, Spring Boot, Android (Java/Native), OpenGL ES, WebGL, Flutter, PyTorch, SciKitLearn, TensorFlow
Game Engines	Unity, Godot, Unreal Engine
Databases	MySQL, PostgreSQL, Firebase, MongoDB
Tools	CMake, Blender, Aseprite, LMMS, Gimp, Inkscape
Operating Systems	Windows, Linux(Debian, Arch)
Soft Skills	Experienced in Small Team Work Environments, Project Management, Agile Teams
Languages	English, Bengali, Hindi

EXPERIENCE

Software Development Engineer - Graphics (Remote) (Full-time) Snaptrude

Dec 2023 - Present New York, USA

- Part of the Software Development Graphics team working on the Architectural, Engineering, and Construction(AEC) automation software product known as Snaptrude
- Regularly working with a software stack of about 27 different technologies in total.

Junior Unity Developer (Contract Remote) Full-time Viga Entertainment Technology

Jun 2023 - Dec 2023 Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

- Worked on a Unity WebGL-based real-time metaverse project development and optimization, reducing loading times by 80%.
- Implemented Unity C# and Javascript/WebGL interactions making 2 different templates for supporting more than 5 platforms.
- Created a real-time video-texture streaming system from VideoJS to support video playback of 20 different formats inside of Unity WebGL.

Jan 2022 - Jun 2022 Bengaluru, Karnataka, India

Viga Entertainment Technology

- Performed general bug fixing code-cleanup, and development for a project in C++/Qt consisting of more than 30 thousand lines.
- Developed a streaming asset management system for Unity/WebGL project, reducing loading times by more than 50%.

Upwork Contractor (Part-time) *Top-rated*

Jun 2022 - Present

Upwork Profile

- Did a lot of related to C++, OpenGL, SDL, Shaders and Unity(C#) with a 100% job success score and an average 5-star feedback, earning top-rated status.
- Handled communication and delivery of projects with more than 10 clients from diverse backgrounds and motivations.

PROJECTS

BlazeTracer - C++

* Implemented path tracing renderer with the help of "Ray tracing in A Weekend Book"	[GitHub] [Book]
Series	
* Followed the tutorial and used my own knowledge of C++ multi-threading to optimize	
efficiency.	

Blaze Renderer - C++/ OpenGL

* Designed the architecture for a basic real-time 3D application for Desktop/OpenGL	[GitHub] [Resource]
platform	
* Applied knowledge of GLSL, Modern OpenGL, Shading pipelines, basic lighting and	
shading techniques	

Chip 8 Emulator - C++/SDL

* Implemented an emulation of virtual hardware instruction set for the Chip-8 system	[GitHub] [Resource]
* Used SDL2 to display graphics and play audio	

Game Of Life - C/C++/ OpenGL

* Developed implementations and visualization of Conway's Game of Life, Basic Sand,	[GitHub] [Resource]
and Water finite automata.	
* Used OpenGL and GLFW to render the automata systems.	
* Used as a tool to study during Academic Course CSE-4703 (Theory of Computation)	
(IUT)	

Bonk-Em-Good - Unity / C#

* Won 1^{st} place in the jam	[GitHub] [Itch]
* Created a game with 3D arcade style, beat-em-up with a unique twist	

Light's End - Unity / C#

* Designed the art, VFX, and Music all from scratch	[GitHub]	
* Submitted for Lab project CSE-4552 (Computer Graphics & Multimedia Systems)		
(IUT)		

EXTRA-CURRICULAR ACTIVITIES

• Designed, Edited, and Published 2 magazines as the Vice President of ICT & Graphics, NDC English Club